你在那畫什麼呢
一個假想的約束場 只有飛盤那麼大
用作連接平行宇宙的通道
也就是蟲洞
噢 你是蟲把腦子鑽了個洞吧
很多科學家相信接觸外星生物
對人類可能會造成惡果
這蟲洞只有飛盤大小  Leonard
用個飛盤就可以封住
所以請淡定
你還指望我造出這東西?
我指望你用它把下巴上的布丁擦乾淨
先生們再會
你們發現Sheldon總是在2點45就遁走嗎?
真的?
他大概只是去上趟廁所吧
那可不是 他每天早上8點去上廁所
只有週五的高纖維食品會產生
1點45和7點10分的附加排泄次數
你這都知道 真是太悲催了
哎 這只是傷心太平洋裡一滴水而已
我正在看他的公共日曆
2點45到3點05 啥也沒有
昨天 2點45到3點05 啥也沒有
上周 啥也沒有
上個月 啥也沒有
那段時間裡 他從來沒有任何計劃
一天裡的20分鐘 完全不知所蹤
我們得弄清楚他去了哪兒
喔 太激動了
跟我舉辦的謀殺推理餐會一樣刺激
是啊 誰謀殺了我人生中的
三個週六夜晚的那案子哈?
Koothrapali上校在廚房
用橄欖碎末殺的
那是橄欖蘸醬 你們兩個挫人
-=伊甸園字幕站  http://ytet.org/=-
榮譽出品
翻譯: elequent Hollie 王棫垚 無知白薯 阿公
校對: 阿公
第六季 第八集
今天工作怎樣?
我整個下午都在忙著生成同位素的
純結晶體用來做中微子探測
聽起來挺有意思的
就是很有意思啊
挺好 至少沒猜錯
你在跟誰聊呢
就剛在學校認識的
不錯啊 我們還在約會 對吧?
放輕鬆 他只是個朋友
我們在一起準備口頭報告
他人很好
不好意思 剛剛是什麼來著
我聽到"口"就風中凌亂了
你夠了
他剛從倫敦搬過來 好嗎?
在這人生地不熟的
那好啊 英式口音 號稱最性感的口音
不對不對
還有法國口音 意大利口音
你說得對 英式口音確實最好
那你告訴他 你有男朋友了嗎
沒提到這茬呢
好吧 那你應該告訴人家
那我怎麼開口啊
你就說 "現在沒空"
"跟男友在一起 英格蘭挫你也挫
米國至高"
好吧
"跟男友在一起 待會說"
- 高興了吧?
- 是的 多謝
他怎麼回的?
沒啥
到底是啥?
"你男朋友讓你這麼說的吧?"
我恨這個人
別這樣啦
得了 相信我 他想泡你呢
他沒有 我們只是朋友而已
這有問題嗎?
他明天還要過來準備呢
什麼? 來這兒?
如果讓你不舒服
我可以換個學習夥伴
但是作業下周就截止了
每個人都已經有學習夥伴了
所以這門課我估計就廢了
換吧 真好 多謝哦
2點44 時間剛好
嘿 Sheldon
你們好啊
Raj和我準備去遺傳學實驗室
跟夜光小兔兔玩玩
要去嗎?
多謝 不用了
你確定?
關燈後就會像一場激光秀一樣
它還會隨地大小便
我確定不要去 你們玩得開心
你要去哪
你們去哪
- 我們剛剛說了啊
- 我剛才也說了啊
你哪有說
那我們口供不一 法庭見
我們要不要跟蹤他
不知道 我很糾結
既想知道他去哪兒 又想和小兔兔玩
你們好啊
嘿 Alex 你知道你老闆剛才去哪了嗎
- 不知道
- 你不知道他的行程?
我知道燈芯絨褲子很吵
必須去換條"安靜"點的褲子
走吧
真想她能脫下那條褲子...
換上條時髦點的
他就是來這兒?
裡面有什麼?
我覺得是個舊庫房
他每天在這待20分鐘能幹些什麼?
肯定不是練20分鐘的腹肌
要是的話 他的腹肌會壯些
有動靜嗎?
還沒
你幹嗎呢?
偷聽啊
你就不能換個邊聽嗎?
我做什麼都不如你的意是吧?
他到底在這幹嗎來了?
他就是個怪人
搞不好他把Leonard Nimoy鎖在這了
("星際迷航"Spock扮演者)
要不就是比爾蓋茨或者霍金
他幹嗎要鎖住霍金?
Howard 拜託
你不能因為別人殘疾就歧視他
這樣不好
如果你好奇我為何要在這偷窺
那我就告訴你
我想看看那個來看Penny的人長啥樣
老實說 我不知道你在家
其實沒什麼大不了的
他們只是一起上歷史課 做課題
我幹嗎在乎這麼多呢
我不在意
你只是這麼想而已
傻透了
這有什麼好擔心的
我不確定
從統計學上來說
你確實該擔心一二
什麼意思
假設你的相貌是平均水平
馬上 世上50%的男人都比你帥
15億的美男子都等著找你麻煩呢
好吧 這只是就外表來說
我還有很多方面高於平均水平呢
起碼不是身高 視力 運動細胞
奶製品承受能力
我是指心理成熟度這類的
你剛才還擠貓眼裡偷窺你女友
你還是當做不知道我在家吧
我不是說你毫無吸引力
至少選擇朋友的眼光無懈可擊
睡覺也挺老實的
還有最重要的是
你會給我買我最愛的葡萄
比起滿冰箱壞葡萄的打鼾男
你是還蠻不錯的
跟這些沒關係
我相信Penny是在乎我的
不至於和那傢伙有什麼
要是他會催眠術就說不定了
什麼?
雖然 這是個小概率事件
搞不好她和他滾了床單
自己還不知道呢
你別瞎扯了好嗎
我瞎扯?
人心捉摸不透的 Leonard
他們共赴巫山時
搞不好她以為自己是小雞在啄米呢
瞧瞧我們 半夜三更 鬼鬼祟祟
好像一對夜賊
我覺得我們更像忍者
我不要當忍者
我要當夜賊
好吧 我做忍者 你做夜賊
不行 咱倆要保持一致
好吧 那就忍者
謝謝您
不過下次 咱要當夜賊
上鎖了
你確定嗎
當然 必須確定
你來放哨 我去...
確實鎖了
你好好把風
我分分鐘就能打開
你什麼時候學會撬鎖的
我初中開始表演魔術那會兒
我覺得自己能做脫身術大師
就像Harry Houdini
結果如何
還不錯啦
朋友 人氣 派對 我都成功擺脫了
成功 準備好了嗎
- 等等
- 怎麼了
Sheldon非常聰明
這件事他很想保密
是啊 所以呢
會不會有陷阱機關呀
別擔心 我比他厲害
那就好 你有啥計劃...
還活著嗎
是啊
到底什麼意思呢
我不知道
方程的解嗎
也許吧
這是質數
加密系統就是基於質數構造的
Sheldon想要加密什麼呢
他讓雞蛋沙拉變美味的秘方
一直不肯外傳
是辣椒粉啦
是嗎
好吧 一大謎團解決了
好了 晚安
Cole 謝謝 回頭學校見啦
再見
我去去就回
我以為你早就走了
你好啊
你要搬來五樓住嗎
不是的 我來看朋友
很好
四樓那位金髮正妹嗎
是啊 你認識她嗎
我...有時見過她
但我都保持距離的 她男友很恐怖的
是嗎
是啊 混幫派的
她說男友是科學家呀
這是他們幫派的名字
"科學家"幫
超級凶的
感謝提醒
兄弟 別客氣 保持冷靜哈
我們不會分手吧
你好 Hofstadter博士
Alex 你好 叫我Leonard就行
Hofstadter博士是我爸
還有我媽
還有我姐
還有我家的貓
不過我確定
靴靴-Hofstadter博士只是榮譽學位
能坐這裡嗎 Leonard
- 當然
- 謝謝
Alex 我跟你咨詢一下
我女友在學校認識一男生
他一口英國腔
好愛英國腔
看出來了 妹子都喜歡
然後吧 我覺得他在勾引她
她說那人只是人很好 讓我相信她
應該沒問題吧
你明白的
你肯定也經常被勾引吧
是的 因為女孩們常說
"哎喲 那傢伙有兩套星際迷航制服
而且耳朵感染嚴重"
"我也好想要啊"
我也說不好 但估計你低估自己了
- 相信我 不會的
- 你確定嗎
你可愛風趣
也許有時候被勾搭了 只是你沒發覺
是嗎
我很確定呢
好吧 我要回去工作了 感謝聽我嘮叨
別客氣
希望半路沒有女生要扒我衣服
拜託 我們是聰明人
能想出來的
代表什麼呢
除了我媽的頸圍
元素週期表第43位是鎝
放射性元素呢
他要造炸彈嗎
那個我倒不擔心
一個樂高死星積木他都搞了兩年
哦哦 可能是這個
43卡路里是半杯脫脂酸奶的熱量
你怎麼會知道那個?
不好意思 想吃就吃 怎麼保持好身材?
等等 "銀河系漫遊指南"裡
生命 宇宙 所有事物的答案
不就是43嗎?
那是42 白癡
嘿 嘿 我會難過的
算了 別搞了
都筋疲力盡了
我也是
我們還有更重要的事
誰管它什麼狗屁43?
我也不管
回家吧
想去吃點東西嗎?
聽起來不錯
他媽的43到底是什麼?!
我必須弄清楚!
嘿 你不是該和你的兄弟們
往牆上噴方程式了嗎?
哎呀 對不起
你居然不信任我
不是 我當然信任你啦
那你幹嗎讓我在朋友面前丟臉
順便說下 他早認識你了
真的?
我冰箱上有你的照片啊
我現在是真正討厭這個人了
你到底怎麼了?
是不是上班把腦子用光
回家後就沒腦子了?
我不知道
有時候真的很痛苦
你不管去哪  即便我在旁邊
都有人跟你搭訕
而且他們都比我高
為什麼人人都比我高?
算了 都是我自己瞎想
我自己的問題 和你無關
Leonard 你怎麼老是這樣?
聽著 和我一起的是你
你知道我愛你的
所以請你不要讓我抓狂
這是你第一次說你愛我
是啊
我們是不是該假裝沒什麼大不了?
那個...
我們是應該假裝 因為...
我快哭了
如果我哭的話 你也會哭的
是啊 你該走了
好的
她愛我
嘿 我是Alex
能和你喝咖啡很開心
如果你還想聊聊 我隨時有空
笑臉 笑臉
這妹子真友善啊
好 有圖像了
看來攝像頭工作正常
還挺清晰的
能不清晰嘛
這可是火星探測器的備用攝像頭
你怎麼弄到的?
攝像頭值幾百萬
但鎖只是十塊的鎖
天哪 他進來了
就要知道了
那東西是啥?
不知道
我是Sheldon Cooper博士
實驗記錄
蟲洞生成器第44次測試
蟲洞生成器測試?
前43個平行宇宙
據我觀測均空無一物
我想第44號宇宙也應該差不多吧
- 天哪
- 我勒個去!
它在啃我臉!
它在啃他臉!
我發現了你們的攝像頭
就換了裡面的錄像
你倆真不知羞恥
Sheldon 我們非常抱歉
是啊 非常抱歉
抱歉?
也許你們還沒發現
我在日常生活的某些方面有些障礙
比如 理解諷刺 裝熟充楞
控制不住聊火車的衝動
這都讓我很累
所以我每天抽出20分鐘的時間
去那個房間
靜下心來 隨心所欲"充下電"
但你都在裡面幹嗎呀?
還有43代表什麼?
你們不用知道 你們不配知道
你們也永遠不會知道
但我現在知道
你製作雞蛋沙拉的秘方了
一 二 三 四 五 六 七 八
該死
我再也踢不到43個了
一 二 三 四
該死
--------------------------------------
本論壇字幕僅翻譯交流學習之用
禁止任何商業用途否則後果自負
天才理論傳 第六季 第八集
What are you drawing over there?
A hypothetical containment field
for a Frisbee-sized wormhole
that could serve as a portal
to a parallel universe.
Oh,you silly doodlebug.
You know,a lot of scientists believe
that making contact with other life-forms
would probably not end well for us.
It's a Frisbee-sized wormhole,Leonard.
You can block it with a Frisbee.
Calm down.
Do you expect me to build this?
I expect you to wipe the
pudding off your chin.
Gentlemen.
Have you guys ever noticed that Sheldon
always disappears every day at 2:45?
Really?
He probably just goes to the bathroom.
Actually,no,he goes to
the bathroom at 8:00 a.m.
with optional follow-ups at 1:45
and 7:10 on high-fiber Fridays.
It's sad that you know that.
Oh,that's just the tip
of the sadness iceberg.
I'm looking at his public calendar.
2:45 to 3:05,nothing.
Yesterday,2:45 to 3:05,nothing.
Last week,nothing.
Last month,nothing.
He never has anything
booked during that time.
20 minutes a day,completely
unaccounted for.
We should figure out where he goes.
Ooh,this is exciting.
Like one of my classic
murder mystery dinner parties.
Right,the case of who murdered
three Saturday nights of my life?
Colonel Koothrapali in
ten with the olive spread.
It was tapenade and you guys suck.
So,how was work today?
Well,I spent most of the afternoon growing
isotopically pure crystals for neutrino detection.
That sounds like fun.
Yeah,it was.
Oh,good,I guessed right.
Who you talking to?
Oh,just this guy I met at school.
Oh,great. We're still dating,right?
Relax.He's just a friend.
We're doing an oral report together.
He's really nice.
I'm sorry,what was that?
I had a little stroke after "oral."
Would you stop?
Look,he just moved
here from London,okay?
He doesn't really know anybody.
Oh,good,an English accent,the
sexiest accent you can have.
No.That's not true.
There's French,there's Italian.
No,you're right,it's the best.
Did you tell him you have a boyfriend?
It didn't come up.
Well,maybe you should tell him.
What am I supposed to say?
Say,"Can't talk right now.
"Hanging with my boyfriend.England
sucks,you suck,USA number one."
Fine.
"Hanging with my boyfriend.
Talk to you later."
- Happy?
- Yes.Thank you.
What did he say?
Nothing.
What?
"Did your boyfriend make you type that?"
I hate this guy.
Don't be like that.
Come on,trust me,he's hitting on you.
No,he's not.We're just friends.
Look,is this gonna be a problem?
Because he's supposed to
come over tomorrow to work.
Really?Here?
If it makes you
uncomfortable,I'll switch partners,
even though the thing's due next week
and everyone already has a partner
and I'll probably end
up failing the class.
That'd be great.Thank you.
2:44,right on schedule.
Hey,Sheldon.
Oh,hello.
Raj and I are heading over to the genetics
lab to pet the glow-in-the-dark bunny.
Want to come with us?
No,thank you.
Are you sure?
They turn off the lights,and it's like a cute
little laser show that poops all over the place.
I'm quite sure.Good day.
Well,where are you going?
Where are you going?
- We just told you.
- I just told you.
No,you didn't.
Well,it's your word against
mine; see you in court.
Should we follow him?
I don't know,I'm torn.
I want to know where he's going,but now
I kind of want to play with the bunny.
Hi,guys.
Hey,Alex,do you know
where your boss just went?
- No.
- Don't you know his schedule?
All I know is corduroy makes too much
noise and I have to go find "quieter pants."
Come on.
Boy,what I wouldn't give to
get her out of those pants...
and into something a
little more stylish.
This is where he goes?
What's in there?
I think it's an old storage room.
What could he be doing in
there every day for 20 minutes?
Well,he's not doing 20-minute abs,because
if he were,he would have way better abs.
Can you hear anything?
Not yet.
What are you doing?
I'm listening.
Can't you face the other way and listen?
I can't do anything right for you,can I?
What the hell is he up to?
He is kind of a weirdo.
Maybe he's got Leonard
Nimoy chained up in there.
Or Bill Gates.Or Stephen Hawking.
Why would he chain up Stephen Hawking?
Howard,please,you can't treat the man
differently just because he's disabled.
That's not okay.
If you're wondering why I've
been staring through the peephole,
I'm trying to get a look at this
guy who's coming over to Penny's.
To be honest,I didn't
know you were here.
It's not a big deal.
He's just in her history class.They're
working on a project together.
I don't even know why I care.
You know what,I don't care.
You think you don't care.
This is silly.
I have nothing to worry about.
Oh,I don't know.
Statistically speaking,I'm sure
you have something to worry about.
What do you mean?
Well,if we assume your looks
are average,right off the bat,
50% of men on Earth are
more attractive than you.
That's 1.5 billion handsome lads standing
by,waiting to rain on your parade.
Well,yeah,but this
isn't just about looks.
I'm way above average
in a lot of other things.
Not height,vision,athleticism,or
ability to digest dairy products.
I'm talking about important
things like emotional maturity.
You were just spying on your
girlfriend through a peephole.
I liked it better when
you thought I wasn't here.
I'm not saying you don't
have attractive qualities.
Your choice of friends is
impeccable,you're a good sleeper.
And last but not least,you
buy the grapes I like.
You're a real catch compared to some snoring
guy with a fridge full of lousy grapes.
None of this matters.
I trust that Penny cares about me,and
nothing's gonna happen with this guy.
Well,unless of course
he's a skilled hypnotist.
What?
While unlikely,it's still
a statistical possibility.
She might be performing sexual
acts with him and not even know it.
Now you're just being ridiculous.
Am I?
The mind's a mysterious thing,Leonard.
He could be having the time of his life while
she thinks she's a chicken pecking for corn.
Look at us,sneaking around in the middle
of the night like a couple of cat burglars.
I think we're more like ninjas.
I don't want to be a ninja;
I want to be a cat burglar.
Fine,I'll be a ninja,you
be a cat burglar.
No,we both have to be the same thing.
Okay,we're ninjas.
Thank you.
But next time,we'll be cat burglars.
It's locked.
Are you sure?
Yes,I'm sure.
Now,you stand guard,I'm going to...
It's locked.
Just keep an eye out.
I'll have this open in a minute.
When did you learn how to pick locks?
When I was starting to
do magic in junior high,
I thought I could be an escape
artist like Harry Houdini.
How did that work out?
Pretty good.
I managed to escape friends,popularity,and
every party thrown in a 12-mile radius.
There. Ready?
- Hold on,hold on.
- What?
Sheldon is a very smart man,and he
obviously wants to keep this a secret.
Yeah,so?
What if it's booby-trapped?
Don't worry,I'm one step ahead of him.
Great,what's your pl...
Are we good?
Yeah.
Forty-three.
What the hell does that mean?
I don't know.
The solution to an equation?
Maybe.
It's a prime number.
Encryption systems are
built on prime numbers.
What kind of secret does
Sheldon have to encrypt?
He's always been very cagey about what he
puts in his egg salad to make it so tasty.
It's paprika.
Really?
Well,okay,one mystery solved.
Okay,good night.
Thanks,Cole.See you at school.
See you.
I'll be right back.
I thought you left a long time ago.
What's up?
You moving into the
apartment on the fifth floor?
No,I was just visiting a friend.
Oh,cool.
That cute blonde on four?
Yeah.You know her?
I,well,I see her around.
I like to keep my distance because
her boyfriend is a pretty scary dude.
Really?
Yeah.He's ganged up.
She told me he's a scientist.
That's the name of his gang.
The Scientists.
They are crazy.
Well,thanks for the tip.
No problem,brother.Stay frosty.
We're still dating,right?
Oh,hello,Dr.Hofstadter.
Hey,Alex,and call me Leonard.
Dr. Hofstadter is my father.
And my mother.
And my sister.
And our cat.
Although,I'm pretty sure Dr.Boots
Hofstadter's degree was honorary.
May I join you,Leonard?
- Sure.
- Thanks.
Hey,Alex,let me ask you something.
My girlfriend knows this guy at school.
He's got an English accent.
Ooh,I love English accents.
Yeah,you all do.
Anyway,I feel like he's hitting on her.
She says he's just being nice
and that I should trust her.
It's probably harmless.
You know how it is.
I'm sure you get hit on all the time.
Right. Because girls are always like,
"Ooh,that guy owns two Star Trek uniforms
"and gets a lot of ear infections.
I got to get me some of that."
I don't know,I bet it
happens more than you realize.
- Trust me,it doesn't.
- You sure?
You're cute,you're funny.
Maybe you're getting hit
on,and you don't even know it.
Really?
I'm pretty sure.
Okay,I got to get back to
work.Thanks for listening.
No problem.
Hope-hope no girls rip
my clothes off on the way.
Come on,we're smart guys.
We can figure this out.
Forty-three.
What is 43?
Besides my mom's neck size.
It's the atomic number for technetium.
That stuff's radioactive.
Do you think he's building a bomb?
It took him two years to put together
that Lego Death Star; I'm not worried.
Ooh,this could be something.
43 is the number of calories in
half a cup of fat-free yogurt.
Why would you know that?
I'm sorry.We can't all eat whatever
we want and still stay thin.
Wait,in the Hitchhikers
Guide to the Galaxy,
isn't 43 the answer to the question
of life,the universe,and everything?
That's 42,dumb-ass.
Feelings.
We should stop.
I'm exhausted.
Yeah,me,too.
We've got more important things to do.
Who cares what stupid 43 means?
Not me.
Let's go home.
You want to get something to eat?
Sounds good.
What the balls is 43?!
I have to know!
Hey,shouldn't you be out with your gang,spray
painting equations on the side of buildings?
Come on,I'm sorry.
I just can't believe you don't trust me.
I do,of course I do.
Then why did you embarrass me in front of my
friend,who,by the way,knew exactly who you were?
Really?
Your picture's on my refrigerator.
You know,I'm really starting
to not like this guy.
What is your problem?
Do you use up all your thinking at work and
then have none left over for when you get home?
I don't know.
It's hard sometimes.
Everywhere you go,guys hit on
you,even if I'm standing right there.
And they're all taller than me.
Why is everyone taller than me?
You know what,this is all in my head.
It's my problem,not yours.
Leonard,why do you always do this?
Listen to me,you're the one I'm with.
You know I love you,so will you please
relax because you're driving me crazy.
You know that's the first time
you ever said that you love me.
Yeah.
We're just supposed to
pretend it's not a big deal?
That's...
exactly what we're gonna do because...
you're about to make me cry,
and we both know if I start
crying,you're gonna start crying.
You're right,you should go.
All right.
She loves me.
"Hey,it's Alex.
"Nice having coffee with you.
"If you want to talk
more,I'm always available.
Smiley face,smiley face."
What a friendly girl.
Okay,picture's up.
Looks like the camera's working.
That's good quality video.
It better be.It's the spare
camera for the Mars rover.
How did you get your hands on that?
Million dollar camera--
ten dollar lock.
Oh,my God,here he comes.
This is it.
What the hell is that thing?
I don't know.
This is Dr.Sheldon Cooper.
Experimental log.
Wormhole generator test 44.
Wormhole generator test?
The first 43 parallel universes
I've checked proved to be empty.
I see no reason to suspect universe
number 44 will be any different.
- Oh,my God!
- Holy crap!
It's eating my face!
It's eating his face!
I found your Webcam and
replaced the video feed.
You two should be ashamed of yourselves.
Sheldon,we're really sorry.
Yeah,really sorry.
Sorry?
You may not realize it,but I have difficulty
navigating certain aspects of daily life.
You know,understanding
sarcasm,feigning interest in others,
not talking about trains
as much as I want to.
It's exhausting.
Which is why,for 20 minutes a
day,I like to go down to that room,
turn my mind off and do what
I need to do to recharge.
But what are you doing in there?
And what does 43 mean?
You don't need to know,you don't
deserve to know,and you will never know.
***
One,two,three,four,five,six,seven,eight...
Drat.
I'm never going to get to 43 again.
One,two,three,four...
Rats.
sync:邦德豬